# MATHIEU DUFOUR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(617) 817-0361

contact@mathieudufour.dev

in linkedin.com/in/mathieu-swe/

devpost.com/mathieu-dufour/

## **EDUCATION**

McGill University, 2018-2021

Software Engineering, GPA: 3.7/4.0 Minor in Entrepreneurship

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript/TypeScript

React (JS / TS, w/ Redux)

Node.js (JS / TS)

Google Cloud Platform (Firestore, Firebase Auth, Cloud Run, Hosting)

Python

lava

PostgreSQL (w/Liquibase)

## **LANGUAGES**

English (fluent)
French (native)
Spanish (beginner)

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a software engineer with two years of experience designing, developing, and maintaining user-focused software. Most of my experience is in full-stack web development, with personal pursuits in machine learning and natural language processing. I'm seeking new challenges and growth opportunities.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WFHomie (1 year, 4 months)

## **Full-Stack Engineer**

August 2021-Present

 React
 Node.js
 TypeScript
 GCP
 PostgreSQL
 Liquibase
 Java
 Mixpanel

- Owned the front end of WFHomie's Analytics platform, using Airbnb's visx charting library for data visualization.
- Full automation of class registrations on the platform, using the Google Calendar API to create and update calendar events.
- Developed WFHomie Kudos, a Slack app installed and used by over 50 companies, and that got featured on Product Hunt's newsletters.
- Maintained a Java (Spring) codebase and PostgreSQL database (w/ Liquibase).

# **Software Developer Intern**

January 2021-April 2021

React Redux Node.js JavaScript Google Cloud Platform Stripe API

- Designed, implemented, and maintained features on the WFHomie platform, often working on tight deadlines to prepare features for clients.
- Implemented a booking system using the Stripe API
- Designed and implemented an authentication and access control system.
- Fully design and implemented a Slack bot that manages user interactions.

Coveo (4 months)

#### Software Developer Intern (Full-Stack)

May 2021-August 2021

React TypeScript Redux Scala NET (C#) Terraform

- Implemented a point-and-click interface that improves the user experience of a crucial part of the Coveo platform, used by end users on a regular basis.
- Improved the performance of connectors written in C# and Go.
- Participated in Agile ceremonies including sprint planning and retrospectives.

CGI Inc. (4 months)

## **Programmer Analyst Intern**

May 2019-August 2019

(C#)(.NET)(PowerShell)

- Developed a desktop application to automate the migration of mailboxes from on-premise Exchange servers to Office 365.
- Wrote PowerShell scripts to automate tedious tasks executed by technicians.